taking a second go with this because I
didn't I don't know I wasn't coming from
the heart I was coming from a different
space and so what I want to talk about
today is rather personal and importantly
to me and that's healthcare I feel very
strongly about universal health care
even though I don't live in America
America is our neighbor it's a first
world country you don't need to have a
universal health care and I feel like
there should be a campaign I said this
before when I think it was when
Obamacare went of the Affordable Care
Act was going through and there was all
be the media against it and there was a
few Canadians that came and talked about
how horrible our health care system is
and I was like okay you know what we
should have a campaign of like cholera
and Canadian and even if we will bitch
at you about our health care system
because it's not perfect I will take it
every day and I would say 99% of
Canadians would take it every day versus
the state system and I don't even know
how to exploit like I've had two brain
surgeries and radiation I had the best
surgeon to do acoustic neuromas people
come from all over the world to see him
I got diagnosed in April of 2005 was
diagnosed I was diagnosed in March and I
had my surgery within six weeks that was
through the whole process of getting the
the team ready
like all of it getting prepping doing
all the MRIs do mean all the nerve
mapping I mean had appointments like two
to three appointments every week for
those six weeks my family flew out to be
with me for that first brain surgery I
woke up deaf in one side because and if
anyone could have preserved my hearing
he would have been able to and I didn't
have to pay for that I didn't have to
worry about paying back medical bills I
didn't have to worry about co-pays I
didn't have to worry about whether
medical tests were going to be covered
by one insurance
and other insurance when I'm sick when I
now have problems I don't I don't like
doctors I have PTSD around doctors not
because they weren't great but because
our system doesn't have it that's like a
whole other topic but when I'm sick when
I have conditions when I start to have
near logical or things that I think
might be neurological I can go to a
doctor and get it assessed we also have
like dozens of other ways like we have a
nurse line that I can call and talk to
when I want to know should I take my kid
to the emergency room we have like it's
in our government's best interest to
keep us healthy and if they don't do a
wonderful job of that it's not like
organic food is is super cheap but their
policy to save money is to keep us as
healthy as possible so they do have have
a nurse's line they have something
called Madeo which i think is in the
states as well I don't know where you
can call and talk on camera to a doctor
and where that's appropriate you can do
that for the comfort of your own home
and it's covered I mean it's amazing we
are there's technologies helping in that
area but you need universal health care
I don't know how to state it more more
strongly for your own interest even if
you are a super mega rich person you
need your neighbors to have health care
because I can tell you if the difference
of my child died or not was that I had
tens of thousands of dollars
I'd be going out and committing crime to
get it I would we still have issues I
mean we don't have unlimited on pay sick
leave so our kids still have to go to
school and daycare sick we still have to
go sick but at least we don't also have
to figure out like how contagious is
this how deadly is this am I gonna die
from this four-day fever I mean I don't
like doctors so I don't take my child's
doctors on day one and two of a fever
I've now learned that if she has a fever
on day three we have to go and I don't
have to that's a personal thing for me
that's not a financial thing it's not I
don't not take her for two days because
we're gonna save money I just don't want
to go sit in a doctor's office and have
her with other germs and other
other things when I know her immune
system can probably handle it but I
don't have to worry about whether me
going to that doctor is gonna cost me my
groceries for the week or month I don't
have to pay a copay I don't have to
worry about all the like the kids coming
in like they can video hospitalized
they're not gonna be we just have less
contagion I feel like there needs to be
a study done on that Canada less
contagious in the States because you
have universal health care I don't know
I feel like we must be we at least can
deal with our colds and flus and not not
pass them on I don't know if
immunizations covered in the states as
far as like if everyone gets it for free
but if you don't that also seems to be
problematic especially you're telling
people to get it and if the difference
is if you're already on the fence about
it and you believe in it that you're not
getting it for financial reasons I just
can see how that would be a problem for
most people well get into that in
different video but today I'm just
talking about a health care system and
how I'm so grateful that I live in
Canada get my that when I was diagnosed
with brain tumors my family didn't have
to worry about whether we have a house
to mortgage but whether they would have
to mortgage the house whether they would
have to cash in all money I mean we
wouldn't have had an option we didn't
have money I don't have money rob a bank
like what what's the option when you
don't have money and people in the
states like oh well you would have been
covered cuz everyone's covered it's like
no no they're not people died because
they don't have health care both in the
preliminary stages where they don't get
diagnosed early enough because they
don't have health care like again I
don't go to the doctor because I have
anxiety around it so that could happen
to me it's not a financial thing but
it's not a financial thing I at least
don't have to add that anxiety on top of
it and um yeah they get blood tests when
I need them I get MRIs why was getting
them every year now it's every two years
I get none of that
cost me anything it cost me time that's
it and whatever health implications come
from that it doesn't cost me my child's
education or my retirement savings or I
just I don't understand I don't
understand how in the state says have
universal health care and how you guys
are voting against your own best
interests
Obamacare otherwise known as the
Affordable Care Act is not the best
system but don't scrap it for something
worse something that's so much worse
like it's a little broken fix it don't
let them pass anything unless it's gonna
be better than the Affordable Care Act
not worse and the Republicans are
probably not the ones to do that they're
not acting your best interests or acting
and the pharmaceutical companies back
just interest the insurance company's
best interests and the people who pay
for their salaries who give them money
who campaign for them like it's those
people have money to pay for the best
doctors whether or not they have
insurance they don't care whether
they're covered their kids are covered
they don't I don't know how they don't
see that if their neighbors aren't
covered and it costs so much more in the
long run but it's somehow they don't so
they're listening to corporations and
CEOs and they're not listening to the
people and they need to be listening to
the people and I don't know if this
video was better than the last one but
I'm just gonna post it please get
universal health care America so where
are your neighbors and we really need
you to